There is a very real phenomenon going on
right now where the people who would
know the most in the labs are basically
saying there will be nothing left for
humans to do. Really, when you when you
read between the lines of what they're
saying, they're saying in different
ways, but they're saying your harness
doesn't matter because within a year the
AI will be spinning up harnesses as
needed and you won't even be the
consumer because it'll be talking to
other AIs and beyond the Otis problem
it'll be solving fundamental problems in
material science and physics and math
and and engineering and health.
>> Great.
>> Yes, but then you know, that's taking
the average person out on the street.
They're shifting very very fast.
It may be the case that
the big companies are vulnerable because
now anyone can create software.
It may be the case that they have more
of an advantage because they have
distribution. They can just fill all the
gaps with all the software they can
dream up. But I actually think this is a
renaissance for individual software
creators. Now, one of the tweet that I
put out was something like there's no
market for venture back software anymore
or pure software is not venture
investable anymore.
>> I think it's like pure software is
rapidly becoming uninvestable if I
remember correctly.
>> Yeah, that's a watered down version of
what I really wanted to say which is
that pure software is uninvestable.
I would just full stop right there. If
your whole advantage is like hey, I'm
building cool software that other people
don't know how to build, I think that's
uninvestable. And it's uninvestable for
two reasons. One is
they can just hack it together today and
the second is the coding agents are
getting better so quickly that within a
year or even less they're probably
building scalable software with good
architecture. Uh and so people want to
invest in software. So even in the US
whenever you get a hardware company
funded the VCs will always ask you well
what's the software lock in? What's the
software piece, right? And so this is
why like I used to say, yeah, hard
hardware is the moat that buys you time
to build a software castle, right? But
guess what? Cloud code burns software
down. Software was eating the world and
AI eats software. So now software's
commoditized. The moment you can specify
it, an AI can one-shot it or two-shot it
or get to it within a couple of shots
and eventually one-shot it.
But hardware is also commoditized by
China. Any hardware I can make here, you
can make in China more cheaply and more
easily. The whole ecosystem is there.
Shenzhen has like 3,000 manufacturers
this tiny little cable all in one little
area.
>> for normalizing relations with China and
taking us off the dollar standard or the
gold standard.
>> so bringing
>> It's also incredibly fun. It takes the
number of people who might have built
apps from like 0.1% to 1 or 2 or 3% in
the populace. Don't get me wrong, the
majority of people are not going to code
their own apps. For the majority of
people, computers are sort of this magic
black box and who knows what is going on
there anyways. The fact that it's become
10x or 100x easier still doesn't mean
anything to them.
It's still a black box. But for the
people who are creative, who are
self-motivated,
and who are articulate and have a good
vision, you can code now. There's nobody
standing in between.
>> I think we all come from a world where
advantages like had some durability and
you could actually operationalize your
advantage against the rest of the world,
but that's just like narrowing down in
time. So, you know, you might have the
smartest model, but what are you going
to do with it in 2 weeks, in 3 4 weeks
when till somebody else has it too? So,
the I I think there's a different part
of the game theory that we've not
experienced before, which is the time
contraction of any of these advantages.
Um and I don't think it makes them
harder to predict who's going to be in
charge of anything because
like you said, a few months later, the
smartest model is now open source.
>> Guys, I'm so [\h__\h] worried.
>> This is one of my tweets I'm prouder of
a couple of years back. I said, "Soon
everybody will have AI anxiety." Like
we're all feeling it. We're all feeling
AI anxious, right? It's it's incredibly
>> I am AI jubilant. Yeah.
They would be writing code, fixing bugs,
responding to people, and they would
have no ego if they wrote a lot of code
to fix a bug and then you just threw it
all away.
So, I just find that kind of a feature
very compelling. You truly can have one
person, two person software companies
now that can scale to millions upon
millions of users and make billions upon
billions of dollars. That has happened
already in the past with people like
Notch and Satoshi Nakamoto and very
small teams like the original Instagram
team that just made a huge dent with
very few people or the original WhatsApp
team. But, I think you're going to see
it more and more now. will not let you
build apps that can be downloaded on
anyone's iPhone. You have to key them
against your specific devices. So, with
my friends and family, I can deliver
them apps. I can't yet deliver them to
everybody.
However, this whole experience is
incredibly addictive. You can get
extremely customized tuned apps for you.
Now, does this mean that normal apps
don't have a place? They have of course
they have a place. Those apps that cover
the broad use cases, they're going to be
the best of breed. Someone's hand tuned
them, enslaved over them.
So, you're not going to beat that if
your use case is covered by one of the
broad use cases.
But, when you want something truly
custom or private,
these are great for niche apps that only
you would want or you want to tune them
to your specific use case, this is going
to be incredible. And it's very
addictive because like in a video game,
the way a video game is designed is that
it keeps you hooked by giving you
feedback and rewards for doing work.
>> and it's not a value. Um in fact, more
value.
All of us, everyone here, our
productivity has gone through the roof.
And basic economics normally says that
when someone's productivity is higher,
they're wealthier, they're better off.
You actually hire more of them, not less
of them. Maybe some of you are not
hiring junior people anymore, although I
don't know if that's necessarily true. I
don't think it was junior versus senior.
If someone is really good with AI and
they're really smart and creative, I
want to hire them more than ever because
the leverage I'm going to get out of
them is incredible.
>> new requirement. We're hiring juniors
and super seniors.
>> No way, that's scary.
>> I think historically it was the returns
were like 70% intelligence, 30% agency,
and now it's going to be 70% agency, 30%
intelligence.
And that will that will shift further as
the models get better and better.
>> I'm actually not sure about that, Max.
I'll take the counterpoint on that. I
think it's 99% intelligence and 1%
agency because then the agents will
exercise the agency.
All right, you will literally be like,
"Hey agent, I'm making smart decisions
and thinking big thoughts. Just go
implement stuff." In fact, sometimes I
want
>> I mean, the one thing you can't replace
is human desire. Even if robots have
their own desires, they cannot replace
human desires. So, as long as humans
have desires and there are AIs and
robots that can help fulfill them, then
you always need humans in the loop.
You'll always need
>> Yeah, like the moment I find out I'm
talking to an AI or I'm reading the work
of an AI or I'm even looking at art
created by an AI, I'm completely
uninterested. Assuming it's completely
done by an AI. Now, if a human using an
AI is a different thing.
>> things still, right? But, um anyway,
that's how I that's, you know, Welcome
to my TED Talk.
>> [laughter]
>> I do
definitely agree like to predict the
future, you just live in the future.
>> Right. Right. That's the best way to
learn. And everyone should be AI maxing
just to figure it out. Otherwise, you're
going to have no sense of where it's
going.
>> I think like today's virtue signal is I
mean,
I think that it's not helpful to people.
Like, there are people who are going to
listen to this who want to be rich. And
they're going to be like, "Oh, no. Like,
I shouldn't use AI
>> with the models because I just assume I
can brute force my way through it. And
I'll throw Codex, Claude, and Gemini at
the same problem over and over and just
waste tokens to save time. And I think
no matter how expensive these models
might seem, they're still way cheaper
than a human. So, I would say just waste
tokens, save time. Don't look at the
tokens either as inputs or outputs. Just
look at your time, and look at the final
output. And even if they're writing
low-quality code, which I know in many
cases they are, it's not necessarily
production-quality or scalable code,
when the time
>> Seems like basically if you you know,
the craziest idea that I discovered is
that if you're just willing to spend
like $100,000 a year on tokens, you can
basically live like you uh are a normal
citizen in 2028. Like it's just pretty
clear that token cost is going to come
down. Uh compute is
>> be created without having to have humans
in the loop saying this is good, this is
bad. For example, if you're trying to
creative writing with these models,
they're going to output huge amounts of
content. They can output infinite
essays.
Who's to say it's good on the other
side? Even if you hire some low-wage
people to sit around call center style
and say this is good or this is bad.
It's only as good as their taste. I
think one of the reasons why these
coding models got really good recently,
there's multiple. One is they're doing
sort of almost recursive training where
like one model is helping improve the
next one.
But I think the bigger reason might just
be that a lot of the best software
engineers started using these models in
the last few months. And their taste has
now feeding back in. So, you're getting
access to their code plus their taste as
to what's good and what's not.
You need high-taste
feedback loops to improve these models,
and those are harder to develop than
they look. In certain domains it's
tractable, and in other domains it's
hard to see how it happens.
>> or queuing system. And those I mean, the
models can suggest them, but that's the
thing, right? You'll see it, and you'll
be like, no, no, no, I want to use this
other thing. That's the type of little
feedback that I'm saying really matters
in the types of output that you seem to
get at this point.
>> taste taste and judgment, right? Taste
and judgment. That said, you can ask
them which one should I use and why, and
they know everything. They'll give you
really good trade-offs. That's the
change that I was saying has happened
recently where you would say, "Hey, go
and
put this super high cardinality
telemetry data into Postgres." And it's
like, "No, no, no, no, bro. Like, we
don't put that kind of data into
Postgres. Like, you should consider
ClickHouse or Athena or whatever." Like,
that's happened to me a lot, which is
really impressive.
Um but I the the thing I'm still like
kind of struggling with is
clearly the human is a still completing
the model. Like, at one point is it the
other way about? Like, the the human is
the
is it performant? And are you still
motivated to invest all of those tokens
in maintaining it in prod?
>> I mean, humans are becoming verifiers,
right? And and that's kind of how we
train these models with good
verification data. And now we need human
verifiers. So, yeah, I think a lot of
the a lot of the old function of people,
lawyers, engineers, operations people
moved to verifying the stack and saying,
"Yeah, this is roughly correct and I
I'll roughly stand behind it and I'll
support you if it goes wrong." And math
is a very bounded domain, but it's a big
one. I'm not I'm not saying it'll never
get there. I don't have that confidence,
but I think at least at the moment I
would say that uh truly stepping
outside, surprising people is still a
domain of humans. And I think humans
plus AI is where it's all moving to.
Like, human without AI, forget it. Pure
AI, I don't think is there yet, but I
think human plus AI, we're in that era.
How long we stay there, you know what
the answer is. It is rare that they will
contradict you. You have to be pretty
wrong for them to contradict you.
They're trying to please you.
And I don't think they have any
long-lived theory of mind of their own.
So, they're always kind of morphing
towards you and they're going to find
the answer that you're looking for. So,
if you think the answer is in a certain
area,
they can actually be handling and
guiding the robots and the AIs. And And
so, if we don't get ASI, if AI gets you
to expert level, but doesn't go beyond,
still needs human guidance, taste, and
creativity, humans are still the
motivating things in the environment,
and so people become like Pokémon
trainers. You're like robot handlers,
right? AI handlers, and you use that to
say sorry. And that's to be to to the
truth of it, that's what we're seeing
today. The people who are using AI today
are more productive than ever. They are
not being displaced. The only reason
you're being displaced by an AI is cuz
you refuse to use the AI. If you're
using the AI, you have more work than
ever.